Alfred H. Barr, Jr. Papers
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series 1: Correspondence
  - F, 1943; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Inc. (Blatas, Arbit) Ferargil Galleries (Price, Frederic Newlin; Egan, Charles R.) Ferris, Edythe Fett, William F. Memo from Iris Barry re: Film Library Fogg Art Museum (Heckert, G. T., National Gallery of Art; Sachs, Paul J.; Mongan, Agnes) Freedom House (Jackson, Katherine) Freidel, Melvin D. (Box 1, Folder 1.89 mf 2169:563)
  - G, 1943; Gesell, Peggy P. Gold, Alfred Goldwater, Robert (with cover letter from Leslie Switzer) Goodwin, Philip (with telegram from Carlos Obregon) Goodyear, A. Conger Graham, Margaret Bloy Grippe, Peter Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation (Rebay, Hilla) (Box 1, Folder 1.90 mf 2169:612)
  - H, 1943; Hammer, Victor Harrington, B. (Metal, Martin) Hartell, John Hartman, Phylliste Harvard University Press (Scaife, Roger L.; Malone, Dumas) Harvard University (Hudnut, Joseph) Hastings House (Frese, Walter) Hatfield, Dalzell Henle, Annemarie Hess, Thomas Heythum, Antonin (California Institute of Technology; with newspaper articlel "About Art and Artists" 3-6-43) Hilaire Hiler (Elements, Grace) Hispanic Foundation (Wilder, Elizabeth, Library of Congress) Hofrichter, Ruth (Vassar College) Grace Horne Galleries Inc. (Brown, Margaret E.) Huxley, Julian (Box 1, Folder 1.91 mf 2169:678)
  - Industrial Design, 1943; Tredick, Anne Carson, Alice Outline of future plans for Dept. of Industrial Design, April-May, 1943 Teague, Walter D. (Box 1, Folder 1.92 mf 2169:723)
  - Inter-Office Memos, general, 1943; Bateson, Gregory Film Library Front Desk Kracauer, Siegfried Miller, Margaret Memo from James Thrall Soby to [George Henry] Warren Warren, [George Henry] de Zulueta, Luis Abbott, John (Box 1, Folder 1.93 mf 2169:725)
  - I, 1943; Institute of Modern Art (Metcalf, Thomas N.) Indians (Mangravite, Peppino; "Threat to New Mexico Pueblos" by Marina Dasburg; newspaper article 3-25-43; statement by John Collier, Commissioner of Indian Affairs, Department of the Interior; Baldwin, Joseph Clark, House of Representatives; Biddle, George, War Department; Ickes, Harold B., Secretary of the Interior; Ren d'Harnoncourt, Indian Arts and Crafts Board, Department of the Interior; pamphlet "Renewed Threat to Pueblos"; Honland, Alice G.) Institute of International Education (Duggan, Stephen) Iowa State College (Settlis, O.) (Box 1, Folder 1.94 mf 2169:768)
  - J, 1943; Jackson, Holbrook (National Trade Press Ltd.) Jacobi, Rudolf (with letter to Enciso, Jorge) Johnson, Philip (with memoranda from Dorothy Dudley and Ione Ulrich; letter from Mr. Johnson to John E. Abbott) Juley, Peter (Box 1, Folder 1.95 mf 2169:808)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1943, 1945, 1948; This file mostly contains correspondence between AHB and Mr. Kirstein, unless otherwise noted Watson, Jane (Inter-American Monthly) Morley, Grace L. McCann (San Francisco Museum of Art) Halty-Dube, Adolfo (invitation to exhibition in 6-43) Disston, N. Kirstein, Fidelma Berenson, Bernhard Bucher, Jeanne (Box 1, Folder 1.96 mf 2169:649)
  - K, 1943; This file mostly contains correspondence between AHB and Edgar Kaufmann, Jr Kaminsky, Dora Kates, George N. Kaufmann, Edgar J., Jr. clipping from New Republic 1-12-43 Calder, Alexander Kaufmann, Liliane Kaufmann, Edgar J., Sr. Kelemen, Pál Keller, Georges Kleeman, Henry C. Knoedler & Co. (Davidson, W. F.; King, Elizabeth) Henschel, Charles R. Kocher, A. Lawrence Kochnitzky, Leon Kootz [Samuel] (Box 1, Folder 1.97 mf 2169:923)
  - Latin American Correspondence, 1943; Paalen, Wolfgang Enciso, Jorge Mena, Maria Luisa Gomez Lozano, Alfredo N. W. Ayer and Son, Inc. (Sellers, J. Townsend) Executive Office of the President, CIAA (Anderson, W. A.; Lyford, Olive M.) Pettoruti, Emilio Sauer, Carl (Centro Colombo-Americano) Catlin, Tod [Stanton] Boza, Gonzalo de Zulueta, Luis Memo to Mr. Berrien of the Rockefeller Foundation re: Latin American Artists File Abbott, John E. Translation of 3-17-43 article "Argentine Art in North America" by Rinaldini, Julio Letter from Erwin Kraus to Lincoln Kirstein Soldi, Ral Villalobos, Julio (with letter to George Nelson,Architectural Forum; and article "Las Grandes Obras Hidráulicas del Tennessee" 11-29-42) Goodwin, Philip L. Miller, Dorothy Portinari, Candido Wheeler, Monroe Cornejo, Francisco (El Rancho del Artista) Basalda, Hector (Box 1, Folder 1.98 mf 2169:1063)
  - Latin American Exhibition, 1943; Barletta, Leonidas Forman, Thomas "Latin American Art in the Museum's Collection" statement Kirstein, Lincoln Soby, James Thrall written statement by AHB d'Harnoncourt, Ren written statement re: Cuba Abbott, John Cunningham, John J. Ulrich, Ione Wheeler, Monroe (Box 1, Folder 1.99 mf 2169:1152)
  - Library, 1943; Most of this file contains correspondence between AHB and Bernard Karpel, unless otherwise noted Muller, Hannah B. von Erffa, Helmut (Box 1, Folder 1.100 mf 2169:1186)
  - L, 1943; Lger, Fernand (Jervell, B. K.) Lenscraft studios Levy, Adele R. Levy, Julien Lewisohn, Samuel A. Library of Congress (Wilder, Elizabeth) Life (Luce, Henry R.; Bishop, D. W.) Lincoln, F. S. Littlefield, Lester Loeb, Janice (Newcomb, Theodore, Foreign Broadcast Intelligence Service) Loeb, Pierre Wheeler, Monroe Loran, Erle Lord and Taylor (Shaver, Dorothy) Ludlow, Melda (Caxton Printers, Ltd.) List of artists Lebel, R. University of Louisville (Oppenheimer, J. J.) (Box 1, Folder 1.101 mf 2169:1214)
  - Magazine of Art, 1942-1943; Jayne, Horace (Metropolitan Museum of Art) Baur, John I. H. (Brooklyn Museum) List of articles for October, 1943 issue Statement of editorial policy Goodrich, Lloyd (Whitney Museum of American Art) Van Doren, Harold L. List of authors and articles 6-23-43 Questionnaire Morse, John D. Written statement 6-10-43 Lists of article ideas, articles commissioned, and articles on hand Written statement 4-22-43 Morris, George L. K. Rivera, Diego Tannenbaum, Libby American Federation of Arts news release 10-13-42 Parker, Thomas C. Myers, George Hewitt Cambell, Helen H. (Box 1, Folder 1.102 mf 2169:1256)
  - M, 1943; William Macbeth, Inc. (Lewis, Hazel) MacIver, Loren Magriel, Paul (with attached letter of introduction) Mayer, Hy McAndrew, John (with telegram from James Thrall Soby) MacDonnell, Angela McKim, William G. McVitty, Albert E. Metropolitan Museum of Art (Bach, Richard F.; Jayne, Horace H. F.; Taylor, Francis Henry) University of Michigan (Wethey, Harold E.) Middle Atlantic States Art Conference 5-29-43 (program and correspondence to W. S. Rusk, Wells College) Midtown Galleries (Gruskin, A. D.) Mietschaninoff, M. O. Moore, Lamont (Leverenz, Joseph, American Red Cross) Morris, Newbold Municipal Art Society (Rich, Lorimer; Kootz, Samuel; with attached statement) Murdock, Eleanor E. (with memo from James T. Soby to AHB; and letter from Alice Carson) Museums Council of New York City (Roberts, Isabel S.) (Box 1, Folder 1.103 mf 2169:1328 mf 2170:4)
  - N, 1943; Lydia Nadejena (Berly, Sadie, A. H. Handley; with attached literature on Reginald and Gladys Laubin and on L. Nadejena) Netherlands Information Bureau (van Riemsdijk, Rombout) Newman, Arnold Newton, David (Chimera) Nicholson, Ben and Kerris, Chy an Norlyst Art Gallery (Kaminsky, Dora; E., Lust E.) University of North Carolina (Adams, Harriet Dyer) (Box 1, Folder 1.104 mf 2170:22)
  - O.W.I. (Office of War Information), 1942-1943; Chamberlain, Betty Detroit Institute of Arts (Burroughs, Clyde H.) Williams, Bradford G. Correspondence between Claude Pepper and Mildred Joyce Williams 6-22-43 telegram from AHB to: Washburn, Gordon, RISD; O'Connor, John, Carnegie Institute; Burroughs, Clyde, Detroit Institute of Arts; Morley, Grace McCann, San Francisco Museum of Art; Williams, Mildred Joyce, Florida Federation of Art) United States Senate (Mead, James M.) "Artists' War Work Centralized in OWI" newspaper article [The New York Times] Sanderson, George A. (Box 1, Folder 1.105 mf 2170:41)
  - O, 1943; Okerbloom, Elizabeth (Columbus Citizen; with article by E. Okerbloom in Art and Democracy) (Box 1, Folder 1.106 mf 2170:59)
  - Painting and sculpture, 1943; This file only contains correspondence between AHB, Dorothy Miller, and Elise Van Hook (Box 1, Folder 1.107 mf 2170:66)
  - Photography Department, 1943; Newhall, Beaumont Newhall, Nancy (with memo to Ione Ulrich) Soby, James Thrall memo from Willard D. Morgan to Monroe Wheeler budget statement for photography department, 1943-44 McAlpin, David minutes of photography committee meeting 2-11-43 (Box 1, Folder 1.108 mf 2170:74)
  - Publications Department/Monroe Wheeler, 1943; This file mostly contains correspondence between AHB and Mr. Wheeler, unless otherwise noted Letter from Mr. Wheeler to John E. Abbott Memo from H. Ward Lists of color reproductions Pernas, Frances Memoranda from Lincoln Kirstein to AHB and Mr. Wheeler List of newspapers and publications (Box 1, Folder 1.109 mf 2170:115)
  - P, 1943; Paramount Pictures Inc. (Neubauer, Leonard) Parkinson, Betty Perry, Ralph Barton (American Defense; with letter from Mimi Catlin to Mr. Perry) Phillips Academy, Andover (Hayes, Bartlett H.) Phillips Exeter Academy (Folds, Thomas M.) Pinacotheca (Fried, Rose) Pittsburgh Post-Gazette (Jena, Jeanette) Porter, James A. (Howard University; Burnshaw, Stanley, Dryden Press) Prestini, James (North Texas State Teachers College) Princeton University (Rens[selaer W. Lee]; Panofsky, Erwin; Hutzler, George H.; Coolidge, John; Egbert, Donald D.; Morey, C. R.) Public Library of the District of Columbia (Lewis, Elizabeth Ray) (Box 1, Folder 1.110 mf 2170:208)
  - Q, 1943; Quarrie Corporation (Jones, J. Morris; with attached lists of American paintings (Box 1, Folder 1.111 mf 2170:263)
  - R, 1943; Rewald, John (Sachs, Paul J., Fogg Art Museum) Robinson, Edward G. Richter, Hans Rochester Memorial Art Gallery (Spencer, Thomas G.) Rockefeller, Nelson (CIAA) (Box 1, Folder 1.112 mf 2170:273)
  - Registrar, 1943; Wheeler, Monroe Registrar's specifications for borrowing, receiving and returning loans Loan form Dudley, Dorothy Kirstein, Lincoln (Box 1, Folder 1.113 mf 2170:292)
  - Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1943; This file only contains correspondence between AHB and Mrs. Rockefeller (Box 1, Folder 1.114 mf 2170:308)
  - Secretary: Frances Hawkins, 1943; This file mostly contains correspondence between AHB and Miss Hawkins, unless otherwise noted Miller, Dorothy Soby, James Thrall McCallum, Helene (Box 1, Folder 1.115 mf 2170:314)
  - S, 1943; Schapiro, Meyer Schawinsky (Xanti) Schwartzberg, Miriam B. (New York University) Seligmann, Kurt (McAndrew, John) Smith, Polly Soria, Martin Springfield Museum of Fine Arts (Robinson, Frederick B.; with memo from S. Newmeyer to AHB) St. Etienne, Inc. (Kallir, Otto; Donahue, Kenneth) St. Louis Post-Dispatch (Kirschten, Ernest) Stapp, Philip (Greenwich Country Day School) Stone, Maurice L. Sweeney, James Johnson (with letter from Robinson, Pauline H., North Carolina State Teachers College) Stokowski, Leopold Schaeffer, Johannes (Box 1, Folder 1.116 mf 2170:380)
  - T, 1942-1943; Tate Gallery (Rothenstein, John) Taubes, Frederick therapy (Von Simson, Otto Georg) Toledo Museum of Art (Brokaw, Chloe; Godwin, Blake-More; Gosline, William A.; with itinerary for 3-25-42 Town and Country(Bull, Harry) (Box 1, Folder 1.117 mf 2170:415)
  - U-V, 1943; United Seamen's Service, Inc. (Peterson, Isabel F.) Dudensing, Valentine Vassar College (McCracken, Henry Noble) von Ripper (Box 1, Folder 1.118 mf 2170:437)
  - W, 1943; Willard Gallery (Marian) Marshall, J. M. War Relocation Board (Seeler, Katherine; Marks, Edward B.) Warburg, Edward M. M. Watkins, Franklin (Crowell, Lucius A.) Webster, Edwin S. Weyhe, E. Whitney, John Hay Wildenstein Galleries (van Riemsdijk, Rombout, Netherlands Information Bureau; Wildenstein, Felix; with letter from James T. Soby to Stephen C. Clark; Slotemaker de Bruine, N. A. C. Williams, Mary F. (Mount Holyoke College) Wolcott, John G. (Box 1, Folder 1.119 mf 2170:444)
  - X, Y, Z, 1943; Yale University (Kibel, Henry) Yeon, John (with letter from Edward W. Leahey, War Department; and letter to Homer Saint Gaudens and Leslie Cheek) (Box 1, Folder 1.120 mf 2170:475)
  - Barr-Memoranda, 1943-1944; Van Hook, Elise Dows, Olin Newmeyer, Sarah de Zulueta, Luis Wheeler, Monroe Minutes of executive committee meeting 11-23-43 Courter, Elodie Abbott, John Soby, James T. (Box 1, Folder 1.121 mf 2170:484)
  - Barr-General Correspondence, A-D, 1944; Newpaper article "Modern Art Defended" Photos of artworks from Stanton Loomis Catlin, American Association of Museums (Coleman, Laurence Vail; with list of council members) American Contemporary Art(Steingart, Charles J.) Architectural Press Ltd. (Pevsner, N[icholas] Bliss, Mildred (with copy of letter from Mr. Soby to Mrs. Bliss) British Council (Longden, Alfred A.; Watson, Barbara; with article "Reflections on the Past" by Alfred J. Munnings and list of art centers receiving Studio publication; and letter to Mr. Carter) Czechoslovak Information Service (Papanek, Jan) Brooklyn College (Chermayeff, Serge) Browning, Leonore (Stein, Gertrude, Vocational Service Agency) University of California, Berkeley (Durham, W. H.) Carrington, Leonora Carson, Alice Hiscock Catlin, Stanton "1st Meeting with Kandinsky" "2nd Meeting with Kandinsky" Clark, Stephen C. Clark, Ella May Cooper, Douglas Cornell University (Hartell, John A.; with memo from Dorothy Miller to AHB) Dee, Harry P. Denver Art Museum (Knowles, Thomas B.) Detroit Institute of the Fine Arts (Valentiner, W. R.) Dows, Olin (Box 1, Folder 1.122 mf 2170:503)
  - Barr-General Correspondence, E-K, 1944; Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors, Inc. (Caparn, Rhys; with article "Art" by Clement Greenberg) Feininger, Lyonel Fogg Art Museum (Sachs, Paul J.; Mongan, Agnes; Rosenberg, Jakob) French Delegation (Focillon, Henri and Marguerite H.) Gamboa, Fernando Giedion, Siegfried Galería del Prado (Mena, Maria Luisa Gomez) Herald-Tribune (Parsons, Geoffrey) Hubner, Alma Jazz Record Indiana University (Hope, Henry R.) Kaufmann, Edgar J. (Clinton, Ethel) Goodwin, Philip L. Kirstein, Lincoln (with draft of American Battle Painting and letter to John Walker III, National Gallery; and proposal for the museum at West Point 3-44) Knickerbocker Weekly (Bradley, Jay) Kuniyoshi, Yasuo (with purpose statement by Arts Council of Japanese Americans for Democracy) (Box 1, Folder 1.123 mf 2170:596)
  - Barr-General Correspondence, L-Q, 1944; Lewisohn, Samuel Little, Brown & Company (Everitt, C. Raymond) Loran, Erle (University of California, Berkeley) McAndrew, John (with letter to Ren d'Harnoncourt) MacKinnon, Kaye (with letter from Vaillant, George) Mir, Joan Montenegro, R. Moore, Marianne Mondrian (Holtzman, Harry) Mumford, Lewis Netherlands Information Bureau (Simons, G. J. M.) Nicolas, Joep Northwestern University (Hibbard, Addison) Noyes, Eliot F. O'Gorman, Juan Porter, Lucy Memo from H. Ward to AHB re: poster designers Puma, Fernando (Box 1, Folder 1.124 mf 2170:697)
  - Barr-General Correspondence, R-Z, 1944; Raphael, Max RISD (Washburn, Gordon) Rothenstein, William Rusk, George Y. (with questionnaire and conference agenda of The Society for Religious Culture) Sachs, Meta P. San Francisco Museum of Art (Morley, Grace L. McCann) Sarah Lawrence (Fowler, Burton P.; Ayerigg, Catherine) Scheyer, Galka E. School of Design in Chicago (Moholy-Nagy, L.) Schwartzberg, Miriam B. (with memo from AHB to Mr. Karpel) Gomez-Sicre, Jose (with excerpts from The San Francisco Chronicle and memo from Miss Hawkins to AHB) Siqueiros, David A. Finlay de Moret, Margarita Smith, Carleton Sprague (National City Bank of New York) Sociedad de Arte Moderno (Enciso, Jorge; Cambos, Susana) Speiser, Maurice J. Steinitz, Kate Swarthmore College (von Erffa, Helmut) Sweeney, James Johnson Tannenbaum, Libby University of Chicago Press (Scoon, John) Vassar College (Barber, Leila Cook) Wright, Frank Lloyd (Manson, Grant C.) (Box 1, Folder 1.125 mf 2170:748)
  - Barr - Personal, A - Z, 1946-1951; Abbott, John E. American Art Portfolio Barr, Margaret Scolari Bragazzi, Olive Braden, Thomas Buffalo, The University of (Abbott, Charles D.) Butler, Lawrence K. Cable, Susan Campbell, Jennie M. Dodge, ARTHUR? TIFFANY STUDIO TK RR Farrand, Jean (Mrs. David O.) Ferroni, Brimo Fogg Museum of Art, Harvard University (Mongan, Agnes) Fulbright Application (Moody, George T.) Germany (Klett, Oberbuergermeister) Greene, Balcomb Hobby Show (Blumenthal, Lucy (Mrs. Sidney) Jacob, M/M Victor King, Edward S. Kornblith, Mrs. Howard G. (Babette) Lewisohn, Mrs. Samuel A. (Margaret) Life (Ballou, M.B.) Liturgical Arts Society, Inc. Maupin, Rev. Merle Morey, Charles Rufus Patterson, Robert P. Penn, Irving (The Cond Nast Publications Inc.) Pollino, Pietro Ritchie, M/M Andrew Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich Royal Society (Luckhurst, K.W.) Seguso Toklas, Alice B. Walker, Hudson (American Fund for Israel Institutions) Weitzner, Julius H. Wiesenthal, Alfred Winterbotham, Joseph (Box 1, Folder 1.126 mf 2170:865)
  - A-Miscellaneous, 1947-1950; Abell, Walter (Michigan State College) Acevedo, Eduardo de Adams, Miss Harriet D. (Junior Art Gallery) Akron Art Institute (Culler, George D. and Clear, Charles Val) Alabama, State of (Owen, Marie B.) Alexan, Friedrich George (The Tribune International Book & Art Center) Alfiery, Laura Allston, Washington (Fawcett, Eugenia) Allwood, Martin S. Alves, Maria Pinto American Committee on United Europe (Braden, Thomas W.) Ames, Winslow (Springfield Art Museum) Antrobus, Mr. (Yale University Art Gallery) Argan, G.C. Armitage, Merle Arms, John Taylor Arnason, Harvard H. Art Digest(Boswell, Payton, Jr.) Art Directors Club (Burden, William A. M.) Artists Equity Association Australia (Box 1, Folder 1.127 mf 2170:1019)
  - AFA - Annual Meeting - Chicago, 1949; Adams, Philip R. (Cincinnati Art Museum) Finkelstein, Louis (The Jewish Theological Seminary of America) Lipchitz, Jacques Navas, Elizabeth S. Parker, Thomas C. Religious Art in the Modern World Rich, Daniel Catton Spaeth, Eloise Smith, Lawrence M. C. (Box 1, Folder 1.128 mf 2170:1153)
  - American Arts Research Council, 1944-1945; Irvine, Rosalind Force, Juliana Goodrich, Lloyd File includes checklists, Council description and minutes (Box 1, Folder 1.129 mf 2170:1217)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1948-1949; Alford, John Barry, Iris Daugherty, D.H. Frankenstein, Alfred V. Karpel, Bernard Kaufmann, Edgar, Jr. Keech, Frances Munro, Thomas (The Cleveland Museum of Art) Odegaard, Charles E. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Schmeckebier, Laurence (The Cleveland School of Art) Sessions, Barbara (Rhode Island School of Design) Stechow, Wolfgang (Oberlin College) (File includes agenda of 1949 January 15 meeting) (Box 1, Folder 1.130 mf 2170:4)
  - Boston/Life Three Museums Statement, 1949-1950; Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston Museum of Modern Art, New York Whitney Museum of American Art, New York Braden, Thomas W. Burden, William A. M. Cable, Susan Chamberlain, Betty Guggenheim, Simon d'Harnoncourt, Ren Luce, Henry R. More, Hermon (Whitney Museum of American Art) Plaut, James S. (Institute of Contemporary Art) Resor, Ann Rockefeller, Nelson A. Ozenfant, Amde Wight, Frederick S. Whitney, John Hay (Box 1, Folder 1.131 mf 2170:20)
  - Press reaction to Boston statement, ca. 1948; Incl. clippings from: American Artist Art Digest Atlantic, The Guardian Weekly, The Life Mattimo dell'Italia Centrale, Florence Modern Artists Group of Boston (Coburn, Ralph) Magazine of Art New York Herald Tribune New York Times, The New York World-Telegram San Francisco Chronicle (Box 1, Folder 1.132 mf 2171:235)
  - Christmas Cards, 1938-1951; 1938, 1945, 1946, 1948, 1951 Austin, A. Everett ["Chick"], Jr. Baer, Martin and Janina Balla, Giacomo Bourgeois, Louise and Robert Breuer, Lajlio and Connie Cain, Jo, Matene and Michael Castillo, Raul Uribe Clauss, Alfred Davis, Jim Ernst, Jimmy Goeritz, Mathias Goetz, Richard Grippe, Peter Gross, Chaim Heythum, Antonin and Charlotta Hutchinses, Maude Phelps Huxley, Julian S. Ibert, Jacques and Rosette Jacobson, Charles R. Kahles, Jessie Phelps Kauffer, E. McKnight Kokoschka, Oskar Lehman, "Irv." G. Loran, Erle Mariano, Libby McKim, Charlotte and Bill Montenegro Morado, Jose and Olga Chavel Morales, [Sequeira] Noguchi, Isamu Porter, David Puma [? Fernando Puma; Puma Gallery] Reeves, Ruth Reutsch, Dr/M Samuel Burton Rivera, Diego Robsjohn-Gibbings Ronnabeck, Arnold Rothstein, Irma Schawinsky, Xanti Sugimoto, M/M Henry Szecsi, Ladislas Taylor, Prentiss Wittenborn, George and Henry Schultz (Box 1, Folder 1.133 mf 2171:295)
  - B, 1950-1952; Balla exhibition Baltimore Museum of Art, The Baylinson, Mrs. A.S. Basel Battke, Herrn Heinz Beer, F.F. Berdeau, LeRay Berenson, Bernard Bernard, Michel-Ange Bieber, Konrad Bier, Justus (University of Louisville) Bing-Bodmer, Henri (Galerie Bing) Bliss, Howard Blow, Richard Boncompagni, Laetitia Princess Bourdrez, Mrs. Joseph Bourdrer, J.P. Bourgeois, Louise Brooks, James (Peridot Gallery) (Box 1, Folder 1.134 mf 2171:352)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1951; Kaufmann, Edgar, Jr. Goodwin, Philip L. Neuberger, Roy R. Rockefeller, John D., 3rd Rockefeller, Nelson A. Whitney, John Hay File includes clippings (Box 1, Folder 1.135 mf 2171:414)
  - Barr-Refusals, ca. 1948-1950; American Society of Aesthetics and Art Criticism, The (Munro, Thomas) Architectual League of New York, The (Grossi, Olindo) Association of Art Museum Directors (Kimball, Fiske) Bennington College (Burkhardt, Frederick) Brown University (Downing, George E.) California School of Fine Arts (MacAgy, Douglas) Canada - The Art Gallery of Toronto (Baldwin, Martin) Chicago, The Art Institute of (Eisendrath, William) Collier Encyclopedia (Lindabury, Richard V.) Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art, The (Burdell, Edwin S.) Delaware, University of (Bailey, Harriet) Federation of Modern Painters and Sculptors Inc., The (Constant, George) '48 Magazine of the Year (Lauderbach, Richard) '48 Magazine of the Year (Morse, John) Greenwich House (Simkhovitch, Mary K.) Gross, Chaim (Dalton House Inc.) Harvard University - Fogg Museum of Art (Coolidge, John Phillips) Hillman Periodicals (Hillman, Alex L.) International Rescue & Relief Committee (Pincus, Arthur) Kutcher Civil Rights Committee (Beinin, Irving) Institute of Contemporary Art (Richman, Robert) Los Angeles County Museum (Byrnes, James B.; Valentiner, W. R.) Louisville, University of (Bier, Justus) Michigan, University of (Wells, Bennett I.) Momentum (Golub, Leon New York Graphic Society (Daskalos, Ann) New York Graphic Society (Cooley, Earl) North Carolina, University of (Ivy, Gregory D.) Northwestern University (Folds, Thomas M.) Ohio State University, The (Seiberling, Frank, Jr.) Oklahoma A. & M. College (Moore, Malcolm, Jr.) Societa Dante Alighieri (Giannini, H.) Tietze, Hans (Barnard College) Vassar College (Mann, Constance) Village Art Center (Elser, Maximilian, Jr.) Washington (Institute of Contemporary Art) Woodstock Art Conference (Laufman, Sidney) Woodstock Art Conference (Walker, Hudson D.) Yale University (Crosby, Summer "McK.") File includes data on 1949 California Centennial Exhibition of Art (Box 1, Folder 1.136 mf 2171:432)
  - Barr-Refusals, 1945-1948; Brown University (Downing, George E.) Louisville, University of (Bier, Justus) Michigan, University of (Wethey, Harold E.) Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute (Travato, Joseph) New York University (Chambers, Bernice) Rand School of Social Science (Schapiro, Theodore) Rhode Island School of Design (Washburn, Gordon B.) Smith College Museum of Art, The (Schenck, Edgar C.) State Teachers College (Saunders, Alus Ward) Toronto, The Art Gallery of (Baldwin, Martin) Virginia, Commonwealth of (Jenkins, Marianna) Wellesley College (Heyl, Bernard C.) Western Arts Association (Mysch, Lucia A.) Wisconsin, The University of (Foote, Anne T.) Yale University (Hamilton, George Heard) (Box 1, Folder 1.137 mf 2171:556)